制作: 星际迷航中国字幕组 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻译: 胡子 & Bruce & EnterpriseH & 是大e呀 & Soulzt & 北窗高卧久息尘
校对: Imprinting & narwhrl
时轴: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-08-20
《星际迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
史波克 这是詹姆斯·柯克
Spock, meet James Kirk,
法拉格特号的大副
first officer of the Farragut.
当年我刚接受任命时
When I took my commission,
跟着派克学习了一周
I spent a week shadowing Pike.
那段经历让我受益匪浅
It made all the difference.
你知道几乎永生
You want to know the worst thing
这件事最糟糕的一点是什么吗
about living almost forever?
你会失去你爱的人
The loss of those you love.
这不是你的错 克里斯
It wasn't your fault, Chris.
我是领队人
I led the mission.
我们得对别人的生命负责
We're responsible for other people's lives.
船员们的性命就是我的一切
The lives of my crew mean everything to me.
我们的职业让我们不得不频繁的面对死亡
Our job puts us up against death
这本就不公平
more than is fair.
你可以选择让死亡赢过你
Now, you can let death win
又或是挺身反击它
or you can fight back.
大副私人日志 星历
First officer's personal log. Stardate...
星历到底是怎么算的
What is the stardate?
日子全都混淆在一起了
They're all blending together.
法拉格特号正在联邦星域外
Farragut is conducting a planetary survey
对一颗无人居住的M级星球 赫利孔γ星
of Helicon Gamma, an uninhabited M-class world
进行行星勘测
outside Federation space, and...
而我实在是无聊极了
...I am so deeply bored.
我发现最近总是忍不住质疑
I find myself constantly questioning
维瑞尔舰长的命令
Captain V'Rel's orders.
对于风险 她避之唯恐不及
It's like she's allergic to risk.
我们在宇宙里是要干实事的
We're out here to get our hands dirty,
是来探索的
to be explorers,
而不是对着扫描数据三重核查 纸上谈兵
not to triple-check every sensor reading.
我明白
I get it.
她想严格按照规定来办事
She wants to do everything by the book.
昨天晚上到现在有什么变化吗
Any changes since last night?
我只是觉得如果规定是我定的
I just think the book would be more interesting
事情会变得更有趣一些
if I got to write it.
舵手
Helm,
带我们去北部大陆上空的
bring us into a low geosynchronous orbit
近地同步轨道
over the northern continent.
维瑞尔舰长
Captain V'Rel, if I may,
如果我们能再靠近一点的话
we could get much more detailed readings
就能得到更多更具体的数据了
from an even lower orbit.
你说的是多近
How low do you suggest?
最近的那种
Lowest orbit there is.
亲自踏上星球的土地
Our boots on the ground.
考虑到地质不稳定的因素
Given the geological instability,
这样做会带来不必要的风险
it seems an unwarranted risk.
我们来就是为了风险的 不是吗
Risk is why we're here, isn't it?
不然星际舰队只要发一颗探测器过来就好了
Starfleet could have sent a probe,
但是他们让我们来了
but instead they sent us
因为有些事必须要我们亲眼所见
because some things you need to see for yourself
-才能真正理解 -舰长
- to truly understand. - Captain,
刚刚有一股未知的力量撞到了
an unknown force just impacted
赫利孔γ星的地表
Helicon Gamma's surface.
报告
Report.
检测到行星地壳发生地震波扰动
There's a seismic disturbance in the planet's crust.
红色警报
Red alert.
舵手 规避机动
Helm, take evasive action.
全体船员 做好冲击准备
All hands, brace for...
医疗团队马上到舰桥
Medical team to the bridge.
这里是联邦星舰法拉格特号
This is the USS Farragut.
我们需要紧急援助 我们遭受严重损伤
We need immediate assistance. We've taken heavy...
长官 有什么东西在干扰我们的通讯信号
Sir, something's interfering with the comms signal.
我正在尝试识别其来源
I'm trying to identify the source.
是那玩意发出的干扰
It's coming from that.
读数怎样
Readings?
还有生命信号
Life signs on board,
但我们的人手只够操作星舰的
but barely enough to crew the ship.
这么多系统宕机
Multiple systems nonfunctioning.
看在贝尔德的份上到底怎么回事
What in Baird's name happened here?
看在谁份上?
Whose name?
那个苏格兰籍的发明家
The Scottish inventor.
无人不知约翰·罗杰·贝尔德啊
Everyone knows John Logie Baird.
救援来了吗
Rescue?
我们的确是来救援的
That is our purpose.
问题是 谁袭击了你们
The question is: rescue from what?
我只看见了一眼 特别大的东西
I only saw a glimpse. It was huge.
他正在内出血
He's got internal bleeding.
我需要把他带到医务室去
I need to get him to sickbay.
我最好赶紧去轮机室
I'd better go to Engineering
去看看曲速核心怎么样了
and check there's still a warp core.
之后来汇报你们的发现
Report back with your findings.
我们会在舰桥
We will offer our assistance
帮助维瑞尔舰长
to Captain V'Rel on the bridge.
等等
Wait.
不光是舰对舰通讯
It's not just ship to ship.
所有的通讯都不能用了
All comms are down.
我们没法和彼此保持联系
We'll have no way to get in touch with each other.
去吧
Go.
但到时候在尽快在舰桥汇合
But find your way to the bridge as soon as you can.
你给我好好撑住
Don't you shut down on me.
增援到了
Reinforcements have arrived.
你们的首席医疗官呢 少尉
Where's your CMO, Ensign?
好吧 只剩你了
Just you, then.
身上好多都是钝器伤
I'm seeing a lot of blunt-force injuries in here.
发生了什么
What happened?
你应该去问舰长
You should ask the captain.
她在四号床
Bed four.
维瑞尔舰长 我是查普尔护士
Captain V'Rel, I'm Nurse Chapel.
你有些脑挫伤 但没有颅脑肿胀
You have a cerebral contusion. There's no cranial swelling.
我需要回舰桥去
I need to get back to the bridge.
嗯 等我们确定了
Mm-hmm, right after we make sure
你没有脑疝的症状之后再说
that your brain isn't herniating.
躺下
Stay.
我们的外勤队已经去舰桥了
Our away team is heading to the bridge.
他们会帮忙的
They can help.
试试绕过主传感器系统
Try bypassing primary sensors.
检查侧向阵列还有没有未损坏的功能模块
See if anything's functioning in the lateral array.
阿尔瓦雷斯 带我们离开这片残骸区
Alvarez, get us out of this debris.
长官 没有传感器的话太危险了
Sir, it's too dangerous without the sensors.
-舰长 -维瑞尔舰长把指挥权交给了我
- Captain... - Captain V'Rel left me the conn,
我的职责是确保船的安全
and it's up to me to return it intact.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
乌乎拉少尉 拉安
Ensign Uhura. La'An.
欢迎登舰
Welcome aboard.
詹姆斯
James.
你这边的乱子真是有够大的
Quite a mess you've gotten yourself into.
看起来这是我的专长
Seems to be my specialty.
你们能接到求救信号真是奇迹
It's a miracle you got our distress call.
通讯都被干扰了
Signal was jammed.
信号干扰也对我们造成了严重的影响
The interference has wreaked havoc with us, too.
但我也许能建立一条视讯连接
But I might be able to set up line of sight.
请求借用你们的遥测仪器
Permission to borrow your telemetry?
完全可以
More than granted.
阿尔瓦雷斯 让我们靠近进取号
Alvarez, aim us at the Enterprise.
准备联系舰长
Stand by for the captain.
派克舰长
Captain Pike.
鉴于目前情况十分危急
I'll dispense with the pleasantries
我就不多说客套话了
since we're still in a critical situation.
威胁目标还在当前区域吗
Is the threat still in the area?
我不清楚
Unknown.
告诉我你知道的信息
Tell me what you do know.
我们当时正在对赫利孔γ星进行地质勘测
We were in the middle of a geological survey of Helicon Gamma
就在这时
when--
坦白说 实在无法用科学术语来描述当时的状况
well, there's no scientific way to put it--
星球瞬间天崩地裂
all hell broke loose.
-因为星球不稳定吗 -不是
- Planetary instability? - No.
一束聚焦的引力束瞄准了这颗行星
A focused gravitational beam aimed at the planet.
被什么瞄准的
Aimed by what?
拥有发射功率如此强大的牵引光束
A ship capable of generating a tractor beam that
这飞船的规模恐怕
powerful would have to be...
比有记录以来的任何星舰
Several orders of magnitude bigger
都要大上好几个数量级
than any starship on record.
我知道这听起来很荒谬 但这是真的
I know. It sounds crazy, but it's true.
我们差点都没发现它 它对我们不感兴趣
We barely saw it. It wasn't interested in us.
我们不过是它的连带损伤
We were just collateral damage.
灭世者
Destroyer of Worlds.
然后它就消失了吗
And it just disappeared?
我们撞上碎片的时候 传感器
When the debris hit, we lost sensors,
通讯 所有重要系统都损坏了
comms, all critical systems.
维瑞尔舰长虽已受伤 但意识尚清
Captain V'Rel was injured but lucid enough
足以下达撤离指令
to give the evacuation order.
逃生舱已部署完毕
Escape pods have been deployed.
我会留下最低限度的留守人员
I'm keeping a skeleton crew aboard
尽量避免法拉格特号沦为需要打捞的废船
so Farragut doesn't become a salvage job.
你做得很好
Well, you've performed commendably,
但还是把你们都一并救出来吧
but let's get you all to safety.
一号 让法拉格特号的全体成员
Number One, I want all Farragut crew
立刻传送到舰上来
beamed aboard immediately.
明白 舰长
Aye, Captain.
全员撤退 从逃生舱开始
Full evacuation. We'll start with the escape pods.
执行吧
Proceed.
派克舰长
Captain Pike...
我明白 我也不会放弃我的星舰
I know, I wouldn't want to give up my ship either,
但舰员的安全必须放在首位
but the safety of the crew has to come first.
这是正确的决定
It's the right call.
我们有严重受伤的患者在医务室
We have some critically injured patients in sickbay
缺少医生照顾
and no doctor.
乌乎拉少尉
Ensign Uhura,
跟查普尔确认哪些患者需要紧急撤离
confirm with Chapel which patients require immediate evac
然后把他们送往进取号
and get them to Enterprise.
马上去办 舰长
On it, Captain.
在你撤离之前
Before you evacuate,
把该未知星舰的所有战术信息传输给进取号
transfer all tactical info on this mystery ship.
以防他们再次出手 我要做好充足的准备
I want to be ready if they take another swing.
我已经恢复了部分传感器的功能
I have restored some function to sensors.
我们仅有的这点数据就交给
Sending what little data we have back
努尼恩·辛格上尉带回
with Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
我现在就传送回舰 舰长
Beaming back now, Captain.
我来亲自把这个交给你
I'll hand this to you personally.
开始传送
Energize.
现在 把你们全部的系统
Now put all your systems...
乌乎拉 重新接通
Uhura, get him back.
发生什么了
What happened?
恐怕连不上了
I don't think I can.
为什么
Why not?
阿尔瓦雷斯 我需要你负责战术岗位
Alvarez, I need you on tactical.
准备好所有武器
Prepare all weapons.
明白 长官
Aye, Commander.
进取号在视野内 他们正在交战
We have visual on Enterprise. They are engaging.
用上所有的武器朝对方开火
Whatever we've got, fire at that thing.
这不合逻辑
That is illogical.
进取号的武器明显起不到任何作用
Enterprise's weapons were clearly ineffective.
我们的瞄准系统下线了
Our targeting systems are down.
现在开火的话作用极微
Firing would serve little purpose
-并且还有可能会误伤进取号 -那我们总得做点什么吧
- and risk damaging Enterprise. - Well, we have to do something.
那我们总得做点什么吧
我们不能坐着干等着
We can't just sit here.
此刻
At present,
恐怕我们只能这么做
I am afraid that is all we can do.
诊断 我现在就要完整的舰船诊断报告
Diagnostic. I want a complete ship diagnostic right now.
这里有一些好消息
Uh, well, here's some good news.
我们不再受到干扰了
We're not being jammed anymore.
好的
Great.
舰桥呼叫医务室
Bridge to sickbay.
我需要尽快和维瑞尔舰长通话
I need to speak to Captain V'Rel ASAP.
查普尔护士回报
Nurse Chapel reporting.
她需要进行紧急颅骨切除术
She required an emergency craniectomy,
而我没有能力实施这个手术
which I'm not qualified to perform,
于是两分钟前
so I beamed her to the Enterprise
我已将她传送至进取号
two minutes ago.
指挥官 你现在是法拉格特号的舰长了
Commander, you are now captain of the Farragut.
我们静候您的命令 长官
We await your orders, sir.
有什么你能辨别出来的吗
Anything you recognize?
可能是克林贡的 难说
Klingon maybe. Hard to say.
这里没剩下多少东西能去辨别了
There's not much left to recognize.
有些看起来年头还不小
Some of them seem ancient.
损伤报告如何
Damage report.
主动力离线 所有网络系统都失效了
Main power's off-line, all network systems are down.
引擎 武器 内部通讯系统
Engines, weapons, internal comms.
便携式通讯器还是不能用
Hand communicators still are not working.
太多干扰了
Too much interference.
维生系统呢
Life support?
在以最低限度工作
Working but minimal.
派一名通讯员去
Send a runner.
口头通知舰员到星舰中部空间集中
Tell the crew to gather in central spaces.
舰体外壳附近的区域会冷死人的
Areas near the outer hull are gonna get pretty damn cold.
舰长 我们派遣到轮机部的通讯员一直没回来
Captain, the last runner we sent to Engineering hasn't come back.
那只能假设我们已经被登舰了
Then we have to assume that we've been boarded.
法拉格特号的传感器日志有什么信息
Did the Farragut's sensor logs tell us anything
能看出建造这艘船的种族吗
about the species that built this thing?
他们的船体对于我们的传感器来说几乎不可穿透
Their hull is nearly impenetrable to our sensors,
但看得出来他们的科技极为先进
but it's clear they're incredibly advanced.
舰长 你听说过阿萨斯里克吗
Sir, have you heard of Asaasllich,
灭世者
Destroyer of Worlds?
它还有一个译法是噬星者
It-it also translates as Astrovore.
噬星者吗 没听过
Astrovore? No.
每个在偏僻的殖民地长大的孩子
Well, every child growing up
都听说过它
on a remote colony world has.
不同的名字 但本质上是一个东西
Different names, same story.
一艘有数百年历史的拾荒船
Scavenger ship, hundreds of years old,
在已知星域的边缘之外游弋
prowling just beyond the edges of known space.
从各种行星以及
Consuming resources from planets
所有不幸与其相遇的舰船身上掠夺资源
and any ship unlucky enough to cross its path.
我在边境附近任职时也听过一个说法
I heard a version when I was posted near the border.
克林贡人称其为查克-卡 意为湮灭者
Klingons called it Chach-Ka. "The Annihilator."
索耶上将也在他的星际制图课上
Admiral Sawyer told a story like that
讲过类似的故事
in his Stellar Cartography class.
地图边缘之外的怪物
The monster past the edge of the map.
无论是不是那艘传说中的飞船
Whether or not this is that ship,
我们已经确定它是一艘拾荒船
we know it's a scavenger.
我们必须假设他们
We have to assume that their intention
也打算把进取号给撕碎
is to tear the Enterprise apart as well.
一号 我需要你和奥特加斯合作
Number One, I need you and Ortegas to find a way
找到重新让引擎上线的方法
to get engine control back online
这样只要我们赶去轮机室
so that when we get to Engineering
一旦阻止能量流失
and we stop the power drain,
我们就能逃跑了
we're ready to make a run for it.
代理舰长日志
Acting captain's log.
这个称谓读着很奇怪
Feels strange to say that.
要不是事态这么糟糕 我应该会很兴奋吧
Under better circumstances, it would be thrilling.
我已经让进取号的军官们
I've asked the Enterprise officers to fill in
去各自填补舰桥上的岗位空缺
for our missing bridge crew.
但他们几乎不了解我
But they barely know me,
而现在我却要他们完全信任我
and now I have to ask them to trust me.
如果我是他们的话
If I were in their shoes...
暂停记录 请进
Pause recording. Come in.
柯克舰长 我们整理了所有
Captain Kirk, we compiled all of the data
与外星飞船遭遇时获取的数据
from our encounter with the alien vessel.
我们都知道些什么
What do we know?
我们的传感器无法彻底穿透其船壳
Our sensors cannot fully penetrate its hull,
因此 关于飞船的构成
so we can ascertain little of its composition,
性能或船员配置 我们基本都无法确定
capabilities or crew complement.
它的弱点呢
What about weaknesses?
根据基础数学知识 按照它的尺寸
Fundamental math? Its size.
对于这么大的家伙来说
It would be hard to generate a stable warp field
要维持稳定的曲速场是很难的 对吗
at that scale, wouldn't it?
这么说 它应该会很慢
Well, odds are, it's slow, but...
那我们就能抓到它
But then we can catch it.
按照规定
Regulations...
按照规定 我们本该夹着尾巴
Regulations would have us tuck tail
逃回联邦星域
and run back to Federation space.
等我们连上子空间通讯中继
By the time we reach a subspace relay
搬到援兵的时候
and get reinforcements,
进取号早被拆成碎片了
Enterprise will have been ripped to scraps.
我们都有亲友在
We all have people on...
我哥哥在那艘船上
My brother is on that ship.
您是最高级的军官 我们都将服从您的命令
As the ranking officer, we will follow your orders.
我只是想为您提供所有的相关信息
I merely wished to provide you with all relevant information.
这些信号是尼斯湖水怪嘴里那些
Those are the signatures
被拆解的外星飞船所留下的
from the picked-apart alien ships we saw in Nessie's gob.
把那里放大点看 得吗
Enhance that bit, would you?
其中的一艘是克林贡D7级战巡
One of the vessels is a D7-class Klingon cruiser.
里面可能有幸存者吗
Could any of them have survived?
极其不可能
Highly unlikely.
船体装甲板将会被拆解
The hull plating would be disassembled,
所有可呼吸空气都会泄漏出去
venting all breathable air.
即便是克林贡人都不能杀出一条血路
Even the Klingons couldn't fight their way out.
这些拾荒者 他们从舰船上拿走中意的东西
These scavengers, they take what they please from ships--
不管舰员的死活 还要把这些技术篡改后据为己有
damn the crew-- and pervert the tech into their own.
我们没法估量他们到底有多大能耐
We've no idea what they're capable of.
查普尔说得对
Chapel's right.
如果速度就是我们的武器 那好钢必须用在刀刃上
If speed is our weapon, then we have to press it.
什么速度
What speed?
恕我直言 指挥官
Uh, with all due respect, Commander--
还是 代理舰长
I mean, Acting Captain?
还是就是舰长
Is it just Captain? Uh...
长官 他们本可以轻松摧毁法拉格特号
Sir, they easily could've destroyed the Farragut
或是把我们塞进那该死的巨大囊袋里掳走
or made off with us tucked in their bloody huge pouch,
但他们没有这么做
but they didn't.
你心里对此有什么推论吗
And you have a theory as to why?
可能因为你的星舰受损太严重了
Because your ship's so banged up
不值得他们去偷吧
it wasn't worth stealing?
那我需要你变出个奇迹了 斯考特先生
Well, then I need you to perform some miracles, Mr. Scott.
按顺序 我们先弄引擎 再弄武器
We need engines and weapons, in that order.
明白
Aye.
把损伤修理好
Patch up the wounded.
尽快让它们重新上线
Get them back to work as soon as you can.
我们得弄清楚
We need to figure out where
那艘拾荒船要驶向哪里
that scavenger ship is headed
这样才能设法快他们一步
so we can find a way to get there first.
就这样吧 让我们开工
That's it. Let's get going.
真是怀念涡轮电梯啊
Really missing the turbolift.
没事 就剩八层甲板两条梯子要爬了
Only eight decks and two access ladders left to go.
哦不 别开枪
Oh! Oh, no, don't shoot.
人活了五千年可不是为了挨枪子的
You don't live to be 5,000 by getting yourself shot a lot.
我们正在前往轮机舱的路上
We're on our way to Engineering.
这可不兴去了 除非你想
Bad place to be right now unless you're fond
被自己汩汩涌出的鲜血呛死
of choking to death on your own gurgling blood.
怎么会这样
Wh... From what?
都怪那条脐带
The umbilical!
跟着我 来
Come with me. Come.
那里弥漫着有毒气体
It's flooded with toxic gas.
它直接穿透了我们的船体
It's tunneled straight through our hull.
它已经接入了我们的动力系统
It's tapped into our power systems,
计算机网络和燃料贮箱
our computer network, our fuel storage.
我们连辅助动力都没剩多少
We've barely any auxiliary power left.
如果我们不想法把它断掉
If we don't disconnect it,
就没有足够的动力来逃脱了
we will not have enough to escape.
既然空气是有毒的 我们需要戴上呼吸器
If the air is toxic, we'll need breathers
才能接近脐带
to get close to the umbilical.
拿上东西 米勒少尉会护卫你们的队伍
Grab them. Ensign Miller will escort your team.
我们摆脱了那东西的那一刻
The second we disconnect from that thing,
就要马上准备好逃离
we need to be ready to fly.
是 舰长
Yes, Captain.
对 给我听着
Yeah, you heard right.
你最好给我管用 你这小破玩意
You better start doing your job, you daft piece of...
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott?
一切进展顺利吗
Everything okay in there?
会的会的 只要我先拆几个东西出来
Soon will be, once I've torn a few things out
然后再把它们装回去
and put them back proper.
然后 这需要多久
An-And how long will that take?
正常的做法吗 两天
To do it right? Two days.
唔
Hmm.
要不你先这样 先确保
Why don't you start with doing it the way
我们不会立即散架爆炸
where we won't immediately explode,
然后再在此基础上做点别的
and we'll take it from there?
史波克和乌乎拉有突破了
Spock and Uhura made a breakthrough.
哦 是吗 哎哟
Oh, aye? Oh.
这艘拾荒船在赫利孔γ星
The mineral that the scavenger ship was collecting
收集的矿物是奥登金
at Helicon Gamma-- it was aldentium.
哦我听过
Oh, I've heard of it.
有几个种族把它用在推进系统上
A few species use it in their... propulsion systems.
附近还有另一颗拥有大量矿藏的行星
There's another world nearby with significant deposits--
沙利文星 就在他们的路线上
Sullivan's Planet-- directly in their path.
有人居住吗
Inhabited?
超过一亿人口
Over a hundred million people.
而且是曲速前文明 所以还有不干涉原则
Pre-warp, so the non-interference directive
意味着我们不能直接警告他们
means we can't warn them.
不过我们也没别的手段做些什么
Not that there's anything we could do anyway.
但听着 我们一定要比他们先到那里
Listen, we need to get there first.
给拾荒船设个埋伏
Set a trap for the scavengers.
你不会是觉得 在他们抢跑了这么久之后
You're not asking me to warp us past them,
我还能让咱们赶到他们前头去吧
with the head start they've got?
这样 恢复曲速动力我没问题
Look, I can give us warp power,
但如果你觉得这东西
but if you think this tub will hold together
都被砸成这样了 在高曲速下还能不散架
at high speed after the beating she just took,
还是少做白日梦了
your bum's out the window.
等离子导管都
The plasma manifolds...
我理解
I understand.
我不觉得你理解
No, I'm not sure you do.
你拿到了个烂摊子 对吧
You were handed a raw deal, all right?
没人会指责你搞砸了什么
No one can fault you for that.
但如果我们把这艘船推得太猛 把她弄散架了
But if we push this ship too hard and it fails,
那就是我们的问题了
that's our fault, not theirs.
这是风险
It's a risk.
但我把赌注压在我们自己身上
But I am betting on us.
准备进入最高曲速
Prepare for maximum warp.
怎么了
What's the problem?
我刚刚绕开了所有安全措施
I just bypassed every safety feature
建立了与舰舵控制的直接连接
to make a direct connection to the helm controls.
我本该立即被电得魂飞魄散的
I should've shocked the bejesus out of myself.
没把自己炸得灰头土脸你还失望了吗
Disappointed you didn't set your hair on fire?
如果剩余的电力连让我触电都做不到
If there's not enough power to do that,
那就更不够驱动星舰转向了
there's nowhere near enough to steer the ship.
这声音是好迹象吗
That's a good sound, right?
这船不会叫得很开心吧
The ship is happy screaming?
是提醒我们动作要快点了
It's a reminder to work faster.
我们能人工点火推力器吗
Can we fire the thrusters manually?
呃 如果我们想死得痛快的话 可以
I mean, we can if we want to very quickly die.
机动推力器使用化学反应点火
The maneuvering thrusters use a chemical reaction.
它们可以手动触发
They can be triggered by hand.
但没有通讯 我们就无法协调推力器的工作
But with no comms, we'd have no way to coordinate them.
没有传感器 我们就只能完全盲飞
With no sensors, we'd be flying literally blind.
为什么要传感器 我们可以自己看
Who needs sensors? We have eyes.
别忘了也没有护盾和偏导仪
Add to that no shields or navigational deflector.
只要我们犯点错误
If we make a mistake,
而且这个情况下肯定会
which we definitely would,
我们就要变成舱壁上的一团黑炭了
we end up a scorch mark on the wall.
通讯问题吗
Communication issue?
那我来得正好
I got here just in time, then.
这可能是第一次
This may be the first time I'm glad
我庆幸自己在1980年代生活过
to have lived through the 1980s.
舰长
Captain.
它直接连在了我们的电网上
It is hooked directly into our power grid,
我们的计算机系统上 还有燃料吊舱上
our computer systems, and our fuel pods.
可以尝试用相位枪切断它
We could try to sever it with our phasers.
释放出的能量会炸掉半艘船的
That much energy would take out half the ship.
找掩护
Cover!
我不觉得他们能透过烟雾看清我们
I don't think they can see us through the smoke.
快把她带出去
Let's get her out of here.
乌乎拉 情况报告
Uhura, status.
接近曲速七级 舰长
Approaching warp seven, sir.
行吧 虽然这船现在基本是拿胶带粘起来的
Well, Farragut may be held together by duct tape
但只要没散架就行
at this point, but as long as it holds...
传感器显示我们已经超越拾荒船了
Sensors indicate we have overtaken the scavenger vessel.
干得不错 各位
Excellent work, everyone.
我们还有多久抵达沙利文星
How long until we reach Sullivan's Planet?
两个小时 如果能保持当前速度的话
Two hours, if we can maintain this speed.
如果之前有任何人跟我说 这是不可能的
I will be accepting drinks in the galley
一会都得来餐厅请我几杯酒
from everyone who said that this was impossible.
当然 是在我们把你们的船救出来之后
After we have saved your ship, of course.
当然
Of course.
报告
Report.
我们掉出了曲速
Well, we've dropped out of warp,
并且失去了所有引擎动力
and I've lost all engine power.
舰长 按照计划 现在我们
Captain, our stratagem has put us
直接位于拾荒船前方的路径上
directly in the path of the scavenger vessel.
我很清楚 史波克
I am aware, Spock.
我跟你说过的 等离子导管全炸开花了
It's the plasma manifolds-- they've blown out.
那就想尽一切办法
Well, then take whoever you need
用你能用的一切资源和人力去修
and get down there and fix them.
它们直接炸没了 没法修了
They are gone! Beyond repair!
我们现在得进船坞
We'll need to put into spacedock now
才能更换它们了
and replace them.
我们 我们把她推得太猛了
We just... we pushed her too hard.
现在只能坐以待毙了
We're dead in the water.
我告诉过你了 我检查过读数了
I told you, I rechecked the numbers
而且检查了三次 三次都告诉我
and re-rechecked them, and all three times confirmed
现在曲速引擎就是个超大号镇纸 什么用也不顶了
the warp engines are now giant paperweights.
我们还有一部分脉冲动力
We still have some impulse power.
但也不够
Not nearly enough.
我看我们能做的就是装死
I'm afraid all we can do is play dead
希望拾荒船能再次忽略我们
and hope the scavenger ignores us.
有可能他们还是只打算去快乐地吞掉行星
There's a chance it'll just go on its merry planet-eating way.
我们的另一个选项是弃舰并使用穿梭机撤离
Our other option is to abandon ship and escape by shuttle.
我们可以派一架穿梭机到最近的子空间通讯中继
We could take one to the nearest subspace relay
然后呼叫星际舰队
and hail Starfleet.
等我们到的时候
By the time we get there,
沙利文星上的所有人早就死透了
everyone on Sullivan's Planet will be dead.
结论就是 两个选择都很灾难
So we're agreed, both options are terrible,
但我们总得选一个 一个小时后他们就到那了
but we have to pick one. In one hour it'll be here.
我们只有一个小时来决定哪个更不灾难一些
That's how long we've got to decide which is least terrible.
这也不是我们能决定的
That is not our decision to make.
我哪个都不选
I pick neither option.
好吧 那很勇敢了 而且 如果你不介意我这么说的话
Okay. That is a bold and-- if you don't mind me saying--
简直离谱到家了
highly unorthodox choice.
行了
Okay.
长官 他只是很担心
Sir, he's just concerned.
他们还扣着我们的人
They have our crew,
而且正在前往一颗有人居住的行星
and the planet they're headed for is inhabited.
我们无法警告他们 除非
We won't be able to warn them without...
谢谢你 乌乎拉少尉
Thank you, Ensign Uhura.
我对情况很清楚
I'm up to speed on the particulars.
没有进一步解释的必要
No need for further discussion.
那我们怎么给你选项呢
Then how will we provide you with options?
我不需要选项
I don't need options.
我不需要你们喋喋不休
I don't need chattering voices.
我现在需要清空头脑
What I need is to clear my head.
但我现在没办法
And I can't do it with all this...
好吧 情况本来可以更好的
Well, that could have gone better.
不可能 怎么可能
No. How?
这是他第一次坐舰长椅 是吧
This is his first time in the chair, right?
他以前也接管过指挥 但从来没像这样
He's had the conn before but never like this.
他表现出典型的受胁迫下的紧张迹象
He's showing classic signs of strain under duress.
他感受到的压力肯定很
The pressure he must be feeling...
啊 太棒了 起初他还无所顾忌
Aye, great. First he's reckless,
现在他又要跟树枝一样一折就断了
now he's liable to snap like a twig.
假设他真断了 那怎么样 嗯
Let's say he does. What then, huh?
我们就要采取措施来
We would take steps to...
解除他的指挥权
remove him from command.
那 那些措施具体是什么
And... what would those steps be, exactly?
作为舰上当前最高级别的医疗军官
As ranking medical officer on board,
我有权评估他的健康状况
it's within my power to evaluate him
并在他在心理上不适合的情况下 解除他的职务
and, if he is mentally unfit, remove him from duty.
好吧 在我们考虑这条路之前
Okay, before we even think about going down this road,
我们应该先考虑
we should consider
他还能工作 这只是他的风格
that he's still working on his command style.
对啊 现在他的风格是装死
Aye. Right now his style is lacking.
这就是问题
That's my point.
我们或许可以帮助他找到方法
Maybe we can help him find it.
我以前见过他处理危机
I've seen him in a crisis before,
他没有被迫当舰长的压力的时候
when he didn't have the pressures of being captain.
他能看到连我都想不到的自己的潜力
He saw something in me that I hadn't seen in myself.
这救了我的命
It saved my life.
我觉得他只是需要有人提醒
I think he just needs to be reminded
他身上也有这种潜力
that same thing is in him.
那我们中就有人需要和他谈谈
Well, one of us should talk to him.
他很显然很激动
He is clearly agitated.
或许风格更冷静的人
Perhaps someone with a less emotional style
去和他谈 会更有效果
might be more effective.
莫雷尔 撑住
Maurer... come on.
莫雷尔 清醒点
Maurer, stay with us.
来不及了  必须现在治疗她
She can't wait. We have to treat her now.
现在 那两个家伙还在外面晃荡呢
What, with those two things roaming around?
别无选择了
We have no choice.
没法对他们造成任何伤害
They're not taking any damage.
进这里 左舷餐厅
In here, the Port Galley.
没有毒气 安全了
No fumes. We're safe.
她在大出血
She's bleeding out.
我需要医疗箱
I need a medkit.
等一下 我觉得
Wait, wait, wait, I think...
要是我们有通讯器和能用的传送器
If we had comms and a functioning transporter,
是能救她的
we could have saved her.
未必 那些离子粒子
You don't know. Those ion particles
就像子弹一样 能撕裂皮肉和骨骼
are like bullets. They rip through flesh and bone,
虽然原始 但杀伤力十足
primitive but effective.
可他们的防护服却异常先进
And yet their suits are highly advanced.
我从没见过能吸收相位枪火力的设备
I have never seen a device absorb phaser fire like that.
这不合常理
It doesn't make sense.
或许他们来自
Maybe they're from some
宇宙中某个永远无法用常理解释的阴暗角落
dark corner of the cosmos that'll never make sense.
我们得想办法解决他们的护甲防御
We have to find a way to get through their defenses somehow.
没人见过他们 但我知道
No one has ever seen them, but I know
即便是戈恩人 也把他们视作怪物
they were considered monsters, even by the Gorn.
相位枪调至击杀模式
Set phasers to kill.
这可是我从伊塞奈特酿酒厂进口的酒
I had this imported from an Ithenite distillery.
我会赔你一瓶的
I'll get you another one.
就像我的一位老朋友曾经说的
As an old friend of mine once said,
「要有光」
"Let there be light."
快点进来吧
Come, come, come.
她的舱室
Her quarters are...
和我想象中的一模一样
exactly what I expected.
在这 不对 好了
Here. No, no. Okay.
在这里
There you are.
不是你
Not you.
你以前倒是活泼
You were once bouncy
又开朗 可新鲜劲一过
and cheerful, but when the novelty wore off,
就有点吓人了
you got a little creepy.
这些破烂玩意儿
How is any of this junk
怎么帮我们飞离这里啊
going to help us fly out of here?
我的老天
Oh, my goodness,
我以前就靠这个操控过不少星舰呢
I piloted many a starship with this.
虽然是8比特的船嘛
Granted, they were 8-bit,
但周五晚上玩这个还挺有意思的
but it was a good time on a Friday night.
啊 找到了
Ah, found it.
拿着
Take.
这该不会是
Is this a, uh,
个人按摩器吧
personal massager?
哦 这在以前可是最先进的通讯器
Oh, this was once a state-of-the-art communicator.
得插在墙上才能用
You had to plug it into the wall,
不过要是有人烦你 你就能让他们一直等着
but if people annoyed you, you'd put them on hold.
应该还有更多的
I think there are more.
所以信号是通过有线传输的
So the signals are grounded,
从一根线缆直接传到另一根线缆
transmitted cable to cable.
拿着那个
Take that.
这样就能防止信号被干扰了
Which will insulate them from being jammed.
我们要让船员们
We're going to have the crew
拆除船上所有的铜缆
strip the ship for copper cables,
然后给进取号重新布线
and we're going to wire the Enterprise.
快去吧
Go on.
我和维瑞尔舰长之前有一局棋没下完
Captain V'Rel and I had an ongoing game.
那是我第一次觉得
For the first time, I think I was
自己快要赢她了
on my way to beating her,
可我们始终没机会结束那局
but we never had the chance to finish.
我记得当时棋盘就摆成这样
I think this is how we left the board.
恕我打扰
If I may interrupt.
哦 你已经打扰了
Oh, you already have.
别停
Don't stop now.
你否决了两个有缺陷的方案
You rightly dismissed two flawed courses of action,
但时间紧迫 我们需要新计划
but time is short and we require a new plan.
轮到维瑞尔走棋 我已经把她逼入绝境了
It was V'Rel's move, and I had her in a corner.
要是能想到她接下来会怎么走就好了
If I could just figure out what she would have done next.
你现在是代理舰长 船员们都在等你
You are acting captain. Your crew is waiting.
让他们等太久对事态
To keep them waiting longer would be...
没有好处
...not good.
问题是
Here's the thing.
我慌了神
I'm frozen.
这倒让我有点意外
I find this surprising.
你哥哥常说
Your brother speaks often
你一直想要指挥星舰
of your aspirations for command
也很有领导才能
and of your affinity for leadership.
其实他原话是
Actually, he said
你不管面对谁
you are not afraid to throw your weight around,
都敢直言发令 毫不含糊
no matter who's in front of you.
是啊 这倒像山姆会说的话
Yeah, that sounds like Sam.
某种程度上 他说得没错
And in a way he's right.
从我加入星舰学院那天起
From the moment I joined the Academy,
我就下定决心要比任何人都快地
I was determined to sit in that chair
坐上那把舰长椅
faster than anyone before me
因为我觉得自己比别人更懂行
because I thought I knew better.
觉得自己比别人更优秀
I thought I was better.
每当我觉得命令不合理时
Whenever orders don't make sense to me,
而且我总是觉得不合理
which happens more often than I'd like,
我总想 该由我来下达命令才对
I always think that I should be the one giving them.
之前 我让维雷尔舰长派一支登陆小队
Earlier, I told Captain V'Rel to send a landing party
去赫利孔γ星
to Helicon Gamma.
我当时极力劝说她
I pushed her hard on it.
还好她没听我的
Thank God she ignored me,
不然爆炸时 我们只能在地表等死
otherwise we'd all be standing on the surface when it exploded.
优秀的舰长知道该何时倾听
Good leaders know when to listen
何时坚持己见
and when not to.
而我连这一点也没做到
Well, I failed at that test, too.
斯科特先生也警告过我
Mr. Scott warned me
不要强行启动引擎
not to push the engines,
可我还是命令他这么做了
but I ordered him to anyway.
我这段时间一直凭直觉行事
I've been flying by the seat of my pants this whole time,
一次次做决定
making call after call
却完全不知道这些决定会带我们走向何方
with no clue where they'd lead us,
只能指望自己碰巧选对
hoping I'd luck into the right one,
结果却让我们困在这
and all I did was put us belly up in the path of
直面那个什么终极毁灭者
the ultimate destroyer.
现在你确实陷入了信心危机
And now you are having a crisis of confidence,
但你还是得继续领导大家
but you still have to lead.
说真的 我也想啊
Believe me, I'd love to,
可我现在完全没头绪
but there's nothing coming to me.
我妈妈常说一句话
My mom was fond of an expression.
「实现目标的人 往往不知道接下来该怎么办」
"The dog who caught the car."
如今我终于有了机会
Now that I've finally latched onto one...
却不知道该怎么应对
...I have no idea what to do with it.
在瓦肯星 我们也有一句类似的话
On Vulcan, we have a similar expression.
「咬到自己尾巴的赛拉兽」
"The sehlat who ate its tail."
不过我要指出 你比那种
Though I would point out you have
四足野兽有更多的优势
a significant leg up over a quadrupedal beast.
你的人类直觉
Your human intuition.
它一直指引着我们 我们现在还都好好活着
It has guided us this far. We are all still here.
我建议你继续相信它
I recommend you keep following it.
好的
Okay.
既然你这么说
If you insist.
斯科提 那艘拾荒船还有多久到
Scotty, how long until that scavenger ship gets here?
不到 20 分钟 但这只是估算
Less than 20 minutes, but that's just an estimate.
对我来说够了
Well, it's good enough for me.
很高兴看到你回来了 长官
Glad to see you back, sir.
我也是
Me, too.
我知道我们开局不顺
Look, I know we got off to a rough start here,
我说什么也弥补不了这一点
and there's nothing I can say that can make up for that.
而且激昂的演讲也不是我的强项
Rousing speeches aren't exactly my forte.
长官 我觉得你说得很好
I think you're doing just fine, sir.
但我要跟在座各位说清楚
But let me be crystal clear to each of you.
即便我之前的行为让你们有别的想法
Even if my actions indicated otherwise,
我也绝不会放弃营救进取号
I have no intention of giving up on rescuing the Enterprise,
毕竟我们两队船员的生命都危在旦夕
not with the lives of both of our crews on the line.
谢谢您 长官 我正需要听到这句话
Thank you, sir. I needed to hear that.
我也需要听听你们的想法
And I need to hear from you.
我们现在掌握了什么情况
What do we know?
除了我们困在太空中动弹不得之外
Besides the fact that we're dead in space,
关于这些拾荒者 我们还知道什么
what do we know about these scavengers?
他们的船肯定有什么弱点
Their ship has to have some kind of weakness.
乌乎拉 你观察到了什么
Uhura, what have you seen?
里面有很多船
Ships, a lot of them,
来自象限的各个角落 它掳走船只
from across the quadrant. It appropriates them,
窃取它们的能力
steals their functionality,
然后为己所用
and bends that to its own needs.
而且它的欲望永无止境
And its needs are bottomless.
它只懂得不断吞噬 让自己变得更大
All it does is consume and make itself bigger.
它变得越大 需要的就越多
The bigger it gets, the more it requires.
然后就会去吞噬下一个资源 就是
Then it moves on to devour the next resource, like...
它永远不会停下
it will never stop,
它永远不会满足
you know, it'll never have enough.
没错 斯科提 你刚才已经找到了他们的弱点
Exactly. Scotty, you just found their weakness:
极度过分的吞噬欲
their ravenous need to consume.
无尽的贪欲
Bottomless greed.
我们可以利用这点来对抗它们
We can use that against them.
该怎么做
How?
这就要轮到你出场了
That's where you come in.
我需要你用奥登金充满等离子歧管
I need you to fill the plasma manifold
直到溢出为止
until it's overflowing with aldentium.
不 不 歧管只是个没用的壳子
No-no, the-the manifold's a useless husk,
况且船上连一滴奥登金都没有
and we don't have a drop of aldentium on board.
我们只需要让它看起来像
We just need to make it look like we do.
随着奥登金衰变
As aldentium decays,
这个过程中会释放出很多反质子
it gives off lots of anti-protons.
我可以用反质子来填充混合室
Well, I could flood the intermix chamber with anti-protons
让我们的引擎看起来像是由奥登金驱动的
and make it look like our engines run on aldentium.
它们会发现我们的踪迹 被我们的排气管吸引过来
They'll catch the scent and gravitate towards our tailpipe.
我们要把法拉格特号
We are going to make the Farragut
伪装成一场令拾荒者垂涎欲滴的盛宴
into a banquet that's impossible for these scavengers to resist,
当它们来赴宴时
and when they come to dine,
就该后悔得肠子都青了
we're going to make them regret it.
舰长已经下令了
The captain has given his orders.
我还是觉得这么叫怪怪的 维瑞尔还活着呢
I still feel funny being called that while V'Rel's alive.
我保证一有机会就会尽快给你降职
I promise to demote you at the earliest opportunity.
等等 所以在这些拾荒者尝试吃掉我们的时候 我们又该怎么办
Wait, so what exactly do we do after we get these scavengers to try and eat us?
这就是这个计划有点疯狂的地方了
Here's where the plan gets a little crazy.
什么这个计划有点疯狂的地方
This is where the plan gets crazy?
幸好你正坐着呢 查普尔护士
Glad you're sitting down, Nurse Chapel.
尤其是你 斯考特先生
You especially, Mr. Scott,
你不会喜欢这个的
are not going to love it.
拉安
La'An!
警告 环境指标危险
你还好吗
You all right?
还好
Yeah.
它没有开枪
It... didn't shoot.
为什么它不杀了我
Why didn't it kill me?
我们可能只有一分钟的时间
We may only have a minute.
该怎么把这死东西从我的船上弄下来
How do we get this thing the hell off my ship?
如果我们不能切断它 那么说服它们呢
Well, if we can't disconnect it, what if we convince them to?
-什么意思 -让它们自愿断开连接
- How do you mean? - Make them want to disconnect it.
让它们尝到点
Give them a taste of something...
难吃的东西
highly undesirable.
我懂了 让它觉得反胃酸了
I see, stir up a little acid reflux?
是的
Yeah.
重子粒子如何
What about, uh, baryon particles?
那它们的燃料和美好的一天就都该完蛋了
That would ruin their fuel and their day.
我们其中一个必须进入曲速引擎下面的
One of us would have to access the waste system
废物处理系统
beneath the warp drive.
废物处理系统 好吧 你去吧
Waste system? All right, you do that.
我得把燃料管道隔离
I have to isolate the fuel line.
还有  拿一个超耦合器过来
And bring a hyper coupler.
拉安
La'An
小心点 还有一个外星人活着
Be careful, that other alien's still out there.
女士们 上次我干这种话
Ladies, I haven't done this
还是给死人乐队打杂的时候呢
since I was a roadie for the Dead.
你这个种族还可以和死人交流吗
Your species can communicate with dead people?
你好
Hello?
是的 是的
Ah, ah, yes, yes.
上尉 找你的
Uh, uh, Lieutenant, it's for you.
喂
Hello?
右舷推进器已经准备好了
Starboard thrusters are ready.
左舷推进器也准备就绪
Port thrusters standing by.
好吧 艾丽卡 小心别坠机
Okay, Erica, don't crash.
拾荒者星舰已脱离曲速
The scavenger vessel has dropped out of warp.
反质子 正在反着质子
Anti-protons... anti-protoning?
我们现在已经美味到极限了
We're as juicy a target as I can make us.
红色警报 各岗位准备
Red alert. All stations prepare for...
好吧 准备被吃
...well, for that.
脉冲引擎准备
Ready impulse engines.
已就绪
Standing by.
她掌舵过多少次
How many times has she helmed?
两次 包括这次
Twice, including now.
脉冲全速 乌乎拉
Full impulse, Uhura.
斯考提 轮到你了
Scotty, your turn.
如果你坚持的话
If you insist.
我坚持 斯考特先生
I do, Mr. Scott.
听我口令分离
Detach at my mark.
分离
Mark.
史波克
Spock?
贪吃蛇咬到自己尾巴了 舰长
The sehlat has eaten its tail, Captain.
拾荒者星舰已被瘫痪
The scavenger ship has been disabled.
乌乎拉 尽快找到进取号
Uhura, get us line of sight to the Enterprise as quickly as you can.
接收到信号传输
Incoming transmission.
是法拉格特号 仅音频
It's the Farragut, audio only.
进取号 能收到吗
Enterprise, do you read?
可算来了啊 少尉
Took you long enough, Ensign.
我也很高兴听到你的声音
Good to hear your voice, too.
我们受损严重 但是我们已经瘫痪了拾荒者星舰
We're pretty banged up, but we disabled the scavenger ship.
告诉她这只是暂时的
Tell her it's just temporary.
能持续多久
How temporary?
不清楚 但这是你们的机会
No idea, but this is your chance.
越狱的机会
For a jailbreak.
左 右舷推进器
Port and starboard thrusters,
百分之十动力
give me ten percent.
我们得关闭推进器 我们还没脱离束缚
we got to kill those thrusters. We are not off-leash.
舰长 找到燃料线路了吗
Captain, any luck finding the fuel line?
我有一个相当可靠的猜测
I've got a pretty solid guess.
把那个连接器递给我
Hand me that connector?
你最好后退一步
And you might want to take a step back.
如果爆炸 整个工程部船体都会被炸掉
If it explodes, it will take out the entire engineering hull.
多退几步吧
A big step, then?
重子粒子正在进入氘粒子流
Baryon particles are entering the deuterium stream.
混合物 正在失去稳定
The mixture is... destabilizing.
趁我们还没被这东西吸走
Let's get the hell out of here
赶紧跑路吧
before we get sucked out with this thing.
等等
Wait.
紧急系统正在重启
Emergency systems are rebooting.
舰长做到了 这些脐带正在脱离
Captain did it. The umbilical's detached.
左 右舷推进器
Port and starboard thrusters,
百分之五十
50%.
右舷推进器减缓点
Ease off starboard thrusters. Whoa.
别减这么多 给我百分之三十
N-Not that easy. Give me 30%.
百分之五十 现在等下
50%. Now wait.
五十 八十
50, 80.
切断右舷推进器
Cut starboard thrusters.
我也不想说风凉话 但是你要撞墙
Hate to backseat-drive, but you're hitting the wall.
左舷推进器全速
Full port thrusters.
推进器控制无响应
Thruster controls aren't responding.
这要完蛋了
That's real bad.
等等 我有个想法
Wait, I have an idea.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
中校?
Commander?
好 右舷推进器动力20%
Yes! Starboard thrusters to 20%.
保持平衡
Keep us even.
舰长
Captain.
是拾荒者
The scavenger.
拾荒者星舰的系统正在恢复运行
The scavenger vessel's systems are coming back on line.
他们正在瞄准进取号
They are targeting Enterprise.
相位炮锁定
Lock phasers.
呃
Uh...
舰长 我们的武器无法
Sir, the grapplers have proven
有效应对那些抓钩
to be resistant to our weapons.
好吧 史波克
Okay, Spock.
你有什么主意吗
What do you got?
史波克先生 扫描残骸中的生命信号
Mr. Spock, scan the debris for life signs.
近7000个生命信号
Approximately 7,000 life signs,
在迅速减少
but they are dwindling quickly.
我们能把生还者传送到船上吗
Can we beam survivors aboard?
我们有心无力
Not even if we wanted to.
残骸的碎片会影响传送器 无法锁定
There's too much debris to get a transporter lock.
舰长
Captain?
那些生命信号
The life signs.
是的 史波克先生
Yes, Mr. Spock?
那些生命信号全都是人类
The life signs are all human.
船体上的标记
The markings on the hull.
我们能看得更清楚一点吗
Can you get us a clearer image?
好的
Aye.
我在历史数据库里找到了这个
I found this in our historical database.
21世纪中期
In the mid-21st century,
在与瓦肯人的第一次接触之前
before first contact with the Vulcans,
有一群科学家 他们认为
a group of scientists believed
岌岌可危的地球环境
that Earth's environmental crisis was too severe
没有复原的可能 所以他们建造了一艘飞船
to recover from, so they built a ship.
他们希望这艘船能让人类文明
They hoped it would carry humanity
在其他世界中继续生根发芽
to civilizations in other worlds.
但事与愿违
But it failed.
这艘船消失了
The ship disappeared.
全体船员
The entire crew,
他们的家人 都消失了
their families, gone.
此后音讯全无
Never heard from again.
我还记得这艘船发射升空时的事
I remember when it launched.
那时我们还没有发明曲速引擎
We-we hadn't yet invented warp drive.
第三次世界大战才堪堪结束
We'd barely put out the fires of the Third World War.
熬过战争的国家不多 其中一个
One of the few nations left standing
在他们残存的航天计划中挑选
sifted through the ashes of their space program,
走遍全世界招募了一批船员
scoured the world for a crew.
可以说
You might say...
那是当年最出类拔萃的一批人
...they were the best of us,
最为乐观积极
the most optimistic,
他们拼尽全力寻找
searching for a way to carry on
延续文明之火的方式
the flame of life.
那么多船员
All those people.
7000条生命
7,000 souls.
他们是初始船员们的后人
The descendants of the original inhabitants.
到底出了什么差错
So what went wrong?
他们为什么会从那样一批优秀的船员变成
How did they go from that to...
现在这个样子
...whatever it is they became?
请进
Come in.
啊
Ah...
只是想当面告诉你
Just wanted to let you know in person,
姆'本加医生说维瑞尔舰长
Dr. M'Benga says that Captain V'Rel is going
之后会完全康复的
to make a complete recovery.
我们会把法拉格特号拖回船坞
We'll tow Farragut back to spacedock.
你只需要
Then you only have
再撑一会儿就好
to hold the fort down a little while longer.
拖回去一艘没了曲速舱的船
I'm imagining the look on Admiral April's face
我几乎都能想象到艾普里尔上将的表情了
when he sees us pull in with no nacelles.
他喜欢毕宿五威士忌
He likes Aldebaran whiskey.
备好一瓶以备不时之需
Maybe have a bottle ready.
可能你会觉得很难受 但你确实做出了正确的决定
You know, it might not feel like it, but you made the right call.
我们遭到了攻击
We were under attack.
你拯救了几百条生命 法拉格特号上的和进取号上的
You saved hundreds of lives, both here and on Enterprise.
未知船只
Number of...
上的预估伤亡人数是
estimated human casualties on unknown vessel...
七千
...7,000.
我可以坐下吗
Well, may I?
请坐
Please.
你知道 我刚晋升
You know, when, uh...
为大副的时候
when I got bumped up to first officer,
我记得我经常怀疑鲍勃
I remember second-guessing Bob--
就是艾普里尔上将
uh, Admiral April-- a lot.
难道他没有为此纠正你的想法吗
Did he ever straighten you out?
没有
No.
他给了我一个深刻的教训
He let me learn a very hard lesson.
重大的决定背后需要肩负的责任
The big decisions-- they seem so simple
只有在别人身上才看起来轻松
when someone else has to live with the consequences,
但当你坐在舰长的位置上 作出的每一个决定
but the choices you make in that chair...
都是你需要肩负的责任
...they are yours to make...
其后果
...and what comes after...
也是你必须承担的
...that is yours to live with.
有一些决定会让你悔恨终生
Some decisions you will regret for the rest of your life,
但你仍然不得不去做
but you still have to make them.
那些人都是人类
They were human beings.
为什么我会觉得更难受了
Why does that make it feel so much worse?
我能说的只有
All I can say is...
同情你的敌人是工作时的必经之途
...having empathy for your adversary is part of the job.
但我没有
But I didn't.
我没想过他们会是人类
I didn't think of them as people...
从头到尾
at all.
然后一切都无法挽回了
Until it was too late.
也许这正是我们应当反思的
Well, maybe that's the lesson.
同情是不看对象的
Empathy isn't conditional.
有就是有 没有就是没有
It's either given or it isn't.
他们肯定看见了我们的模样
They... clearly saw us,
要么他们没有认出我们 要么他们不在乎
and either they didn't recognize us or they didn't care.
无论过去两百年
Whatever journey they had been through
发生了什么 他们已经不是当初的那批船员了
the last 200 years, it broke them.
他们离开地球的时候
When they left Earth...
是全人类中最优秀的
...they were the best humanity had to offer.
他们过去并不是怪物
They weren't monsters.
我们在同样的情况下也会变成那样吗
Is that what we would become in the same circumstances?
我想我们不会的
I'd like to believe we wouldn't.
为什么
Why not?
因为我们对他们怀有同情
Because of how you're feeling right now.
因为下一次你作为舰长下达指令的时候
Because the next time you're in that chair,
你会想起我们与我们的敌人
you will remember we are often not that different
并没有那么不同
from our enemy.
这种认识
And that knowledge,
从现在起
from this moment on,
会永远指引着你
will continue to guide you.
晚安 柯克舰长
Good night, Captain Kirk.